Scooby-Doo! and the Spooky Scarecrow is a animation,
family, mystery film directed by Michael Goguen.
Scooby-Doo and the rest of the ghost-busting gang visit a quiet farm town where
everyone is preparing for the annual Halloween harvest celebration.
Scooby-Doo / Fred Jones (voice), played by Frank Welker.
Shaggy Rogers (voice), played by Matthew Lillard.
Velma Dinkley (voice), played by Mindy Cohn.
Daphne Blake (voice), played by Grey DeLisle.
Levi (voice), played by Josh Keaton.
Sheriff Kern (voice), played by Wendie Malick.
Scooby-Doo (often written as Scooby-Doo!) is an American
media franchise owned by Warner Bros.
Entertainment and created in 1969 by writers Joe Ruby and Ken Spears through their animated series,
Scooby-Doo, Where Are You!, for Hanna-Barbera, which was later absorbed into Warner Bros.
Animation in 2001.
The series features four teenagers named Fred Jones, Daphne Blake, Velma Dinkley, and Shaggy Rogers, and their talking Great Dane named Scooby-Doo, who solve mysteries
involving supposedly supernatural creatures through a series of antics and missteps, while traveling in a brightly colored van called the Mystery Machine.
The franchise has numerous shows, films, and specials.
Scooby-Doo was originally broadcast on CBS from
1969 to 1976, when it moved to ABC.
ABC aired various versions of Scooby-Doo until canceling it in 1986, and presented a spin-off
featuring the characters as children called A Pup Named Scooby-Doo from 1988 to 1991.
Two Scooby-Doo reboots aired as part of Kids' WB on The WB
and its successor The CW from 2002 to 2008.
Further reboots aired on Cartoon Network from 2010 to 2018.
Repeats of the various Scooby-Doo series are frequently broadcast on Cartoon
Network's sister channel Boomerang in the United States and other countries.
The most recent Scooby-Doo series, Scooby-Doo and Guess Who?, premiered on June 27, 2019,
as an original series on Boomerang's streaming service and later HBO Max.
In 2013, TV Guide ranked Scooby-Doo the fifth-greatest TV cartoon of all time.
The film explores themes of farm, halloween, scarecrow, corn.
The tone is lighthearted and mind_bending.